A Guide to the Porter Family papers, 1766-1924, no date
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Porter Family papers, 1766-1924, no date
The Library of Virginia
44163
12 leaves and 70 pages
Porter family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of James H. Chapman of Lexington, North Carolina.
Biographical Information
The Porter family resided in Bath County, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1766-1924 and undated, of the Porter family of Bath County, Virginia, consisting of fifteen deeds, 1766-1908, for property in Bath County including several for land along the Cowpasture River; a plat (copy), 17 October 1794, for 458 acres along the Cowpasture River in Bath County; a deed and an abstract, 29 July 1843, for property along Big Spring Fork of the Elk River in Pocahontas County, (West) Virginia; articles of agreement, 21 October 1880, for boundary line for property along the Big Spring Fork of the Elk River in Pocahontas County; two deeds, 1868 and 1881, for 1000 acres in Rockbridge County, Virginia, along the Calf Pasture River; a will, 11 March 1899, from Bath County; a brief history of the Porter family in Virginia; and a real estate brochure, no date, but post 1967, advertising Windy Cove Farm in Bath County for sale.
Contents List
- Deed, dated 18 March 1766 [1776?]and recorded 19 March 1776, for 195 acres on the Cowpasture River in Augusta County [later in Bath County], Virgina from Samuel Hamilton to Alexander Crawford, both of Augusta County (located in oversize box 104).
- Deed, dated 19 March 1776 and recorded 19 March 1776, for 195 acres on the Cowpasture River in Augusta County [later in Bath County], Virginia from Samuel Hamilton to Alexander Crawford, both of Augusta County (located in oversize box 104).
- Plat, 17 October 1794, for 458 acres on the Cowpasture River in Bath County, Virginia, surveyed for John Dickinson.
- Deed, dated 10 September 1799 and recorded September 1799, for 195 acres on the Cowpasture River in Bath County from Alexander Crawford and Elizabeth Crawford to James Kelso, all of Bath County (located in oversize box 104).
- Deed, dated 21 June 1813 and recorded October 1813, for 195 acres on the Cowpasture River in Bath County from James Kelso and Elizabeth Kelso of Goochland County, Virginia, to Robert Sitlington of Bath County (located in oversize box 104).
- Deed, dated 25 October 1833 and recorded 26 October 1833, for two tracts of land totalling 280 acres total on both sides of Mill Creek in Bath County from Elisha Williams and Sarah Williams to Andrew Sitlington, all of Bath County.
- Deed, dated 12 June 1841 and recorded 10 August 1841, for 120 acres on the Cowpasture River in Bath County from Thomas F. Barnett and Mary Barnett of Bledsoe County, Tennessee, to Andrew Sitlington of Bath County.
- Abstract of deed, dated 29 July 1843, for 1000 acres and 65 1/2 acres located on the Big Spring Fork of the Elk River in Pocahontas County, (West) Virginia, from John Beal and Ophelia Ann Beal of Pocahontas County to Andrew Sitlington of Bath County.
- Deed, dated 29 July 1843 and recorded 5 September 1843, for 1000 acres and 65 1/2 acres located on the Big Spring Fork of the Elk River in Pocahontas County, from John Beal and Ophelia Ann Beal of Pocahontas County to Andrew Sitlington of Bath County.
- Deed, dated and recorded 8 September 1849, for two tracts of land, 150 acres and 209 acres, in Bath County from John Sloan, commissioner for the circuit superior court of law and chancery of Bath County in four causes concerning land once owned by William Sitlington to Andrew Sitlington of Bath County.
- Deed, dated 9 January 1858 and recorded 9 February 1858, for 296 acres on the Cowpasture River in Bath County from Stephen A. Porter and William C. Burger, executors of the estate of Andrew Crawford deceased, to William A. Cleek of Bath County.
- Deed, dated 20 March 1868 and recorded 6 April 1868, for 1000 acres on the Calf Pasture River in Rockbridge County, Virginia, from James Burk and Jane C. Burk of Alleghany County, Virginia, to Thomas N. Burk of Rockbridge County.
- Deed, dated 11 December 1869 and recorded 13 January 1874, for 600 acres on the Cowpasture River in Bath County from W. W. Mooney and Virginia S. Mooney, Andrew S. Porter, and Elizabeth P. Porter to Joseph B. Dickinson, all of Bath County.
- Deed, dated 16 December 1869, for five tracts of land totalling 559 acres on the Cowpasture River in Bath County from Charles Sitlington, Wililam Sitlington and Jane A. Sitlington, William W. Mooney and Virginia S. Mooney, Andrew S. Porter, Elizabeth P. Porter (all of Bath County), William A. Mann and Margaret A. Mann (of Augusta County), and Alexander D. Campbell and Esteline Campbell (of Rockbridge County) to Joseph B. Dickinson of Bath County. Deed does not have a recordation date but it is certified by the justices of the peace in Bath, Augusta, and Rockbridge Counties.
- Deed, dated and recorded 5 July 1871, for five tracts of land totalling 559 acres on the Cowpasture River in Bath County from Charles R. McDannald, special commissioner of the circuit court of Bath County, to Joseph B. Dickinson of Bath County.
- Deed, dated 25 July 1871 and recorded 13 January 1874, for 1/4 interest in a tract of land on the Cowpasture River in Bath County from John B. Porter to Joseph B. Dickinson, both of Bath County.
- Deed, dated 24 October 1878 and recorded 10 June 1880, for interest in 209 acres on the Cowpasture River from Thomas J. Hyde and Eliza J. Hyde to Joseph B. Dickinson, all of Bath County.
- Articles of agreement, dated 21 October 1880 and recorded 10 December 1880, between A. C. L. Gatewood and his wife Mary Gatewood of Pocahontas County and Joseph B. Dickinson and Margaret A. Dickinson of Bath County for the adjustment of the line between their properties along Big Spring branch of the Elk River in Pocahontas County.
- Deed, dated 1 October 1881, for 1000 acres on the Calf Pasture River in Rockbridge County from Joseph B. Dickinson and Margaret A. Dickinson of Bath County to G. W. Fraley of Rockbridge County.
- Deed, dated and recorded 20 January 1885, for 560 on Mill Creek in Bath County from C. R. McDannald, commissioner for the circuit court of Bath County to Margaret Ann Dickinson of Bath County.
- Will, dated 11 March 1899 and recorded 15 January 1901, of Margaret A. Stoakley of Bath County.
- Deed, dated 31 October 1908, for 50 3/8 acres in Bath County between Stephen P. Wilson Bettie M. Wilson, and A. Houston Wilson of the first part, T. W. Black and Laura L. Black of the second part, and W. R. Neff of the third part. Deed is incomplete.
- Partial History of Porter Family, 16 September 1924.
- Real estate brochure, undated, but post-1970, for Windy Cove Farm in Bath County.